Pietro Forino Interaction Designer

pietroforino.com info@pietroforino.com (+39) 3490929514

Profile

I am an interaction designer based in Milan and was born in 1998. Since I was 11 years old I, have been programming web languages, making this skill my strong point in project development. Over the years, I have approached different design methods, soon finding the best one that would allow me to implement a project from start to finish even on my own. I have a strong ability in working in teams and coordinating people and projects, as well as having a dialogue with the client. Code, photography, branding and typography for me remain always and only means: my only goal is to create successful experiences that place the user at the center and allow a concept to be directly conveyed. Currently, my main focus is interactive installations, where physical and digital find form together to create a new concept of interaction.



Experiences

Interaction Designer **Dotdotdot**

Milan, Italy Sept. 2022 — present Dotdotdot is a leading interaction design studio on the Italian scene. My role has been from the beginning Junior Interaction Designer, with the task of helping the studio in moving from experiences based on very complex programs to experiences totally based on web technologies, but without losing performance and final effect. At Dotdotdot I get to experiment and research new solutions to new problems, as well as take a project forward from the initial brief to the final presentation to the client.

Digital designer Freelancing

Milan, Italy 2018 — present During my studies, I always carved out part of my time for freelancing. This allowed me to apply what I was learning in the design field with the skills I had acquired in previous years.

In particular, I collaborated with design studios and individuals on branding and web experiences, as well as in the field of video-making and visual communication.

Internship The Jack Stupid

Milan, Italy January — April 2020 In the 4 months passed by the Jack Stupid, the well-known creative studio, I had the opportunity to support the design, preproduction, production and post-production phases of many projects. In particular, I focused on the part of 3D modeling, video production and subsequent editing of the footage. The experience allowed me to grow a lot on the human and the professional level, in particular regarding to the approach to a new project and to a new client.

Awards, press and other stuff

Core77 Student Winner @ Interaction Design
The Lost Graduation Show @ Salone del Mobile di Milano
Top 8 projects @ The Lost Graduation Show for Azure Magazine
The Next Poster Exhibition @ Designforum Steiermark in Graz
Micromort, the death-based currency project article on DomusWeb

Micromort as case study on SpeculativeEdu

1st place at Nostalgia di Futuro

Merit scholarship at Politecnico di Milano

Pietro Forino Interaction Designer

pietroforino.com info@pietroforino.com (+39) 3490929514

Educations

Politecnico di Milano

Master's in Digital and Interaction Design 110L/110 Thesis: PAIR - Beyond interaction

Milano, Italy

September 2020 — May 2023

FH Joanneum

Erasmus experience in Interaction Design

February 2022 — July 2022

Politecnico di Milano

Bachelor's in Communication Design 110L/110 Thesis: Micromort death-based currency

Milano, Italy

September 2017 — July 2020

Liceo Alessandro Volta

Scientific High School Diploma

Milano, Italy

September 2012 — July 2017

Certifications Language

Eas Milan TOEIC English Certification C1

Milano, Italy July 2020

HTML WordPress Skills Coding WooCommerce CSS

JavaScript Arduino

Adobe Suite Visual

Da Vinci Resolve Cinema 4D + Arnold

Soft Team management

Team building

Effective communicator